# Personal Information

Name Tom F.H. Runia

Date of Birth July 1990 (Leiden, The Netherlands)

Address Amsterdam, The Netherlands

E-mail runia@uva.nl

Website <a href="https://tomrunia.github.io">https://tomrunia.github.io</a>

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/tom-runia-29448435/

## Summary

I am currently **PhD student** at QUVA Deep Vision lab, working on deep learning for computer vision. The focus of my research is on developing efficient video representations using deep learning. For more information, please see: <a href="https://ivi.fnwi.uva.nl/quva/">https://ivi.fnwi.uva.nl/quva/</a>

## Education

#### 2016 - Present Doctor of Philosophy (PhD.) in Artificial Intelligence

- QUVA Deep Vision Lab: University of Amsterdam and Qualcomm
- Deep Learning for Learning Video Representations
- Advisors: Cees Snoek and Arnold Smeulders

#### 2013 – 2015 Master of Science (MSc.) in Computer Science

- Delft University of Technology
- Track: Intelligent Information Processing
- Thesis: High Speed Object Detection, supervised by Prof. Dr. Marco Loog
- Grade Point Average: 8.5/10 (Cum Laude, i.e. with honors)

#### 2011 – 2012 Bridging Program to MSc. Computer Science

- Delft University of Technology
- 30 ECTs of courses in Computer Science and Software Engineering

#### 2008 – 2011 Bachelor of Science (BSc.) in Applied Physics

- Delft University of Technology
- Thesis: Image Processing for Automated Cell Counting

#### 2002 – 2008 **Secondary School:** Preparatory Scientific Education (VWO)

- Bonaventura College Leiden, The Netherlands
- Science and Technology complemented with Economics and Biology

# Professional Experience

#### 2014 – 2015 Research Intern at TomTom

Graduate internship on computer vision and machine learning. My research focused on high-speed object detection for autonomous driving applications. This involved the design and implementation of high-performance computer vision algorithms using C++ and GPU programming.

#### 2013 – 2015 **Software Engineer** at **TamTam** (now Dept)

Tam Tam is in the top three of full-service internet agencies in The Netherlands. As a back-end developer at the operational services group I worked on some of the larger websites in the country.

#### 2012 – 2013 Research Assistant at Delft University of Technology

Research assistant in the Quantitative Imaging group at TU Delft. One of my tasks involved the implementation of image processing algorithms in Java for super- resolution microscopy.

#### 2009 – 2010 Research Assistant at Delft University of Technology

Innovative Design Delft is a small company focusing on data management systems and security. During my study, one day a week I worked on various projects as back-end developer.

# Miscellaneous

#### **Awards**

• Rewarded the **Ngi-NGN Award** in Computer Science for my MSc. Thesis (€1,000) (*From*: The Royal Holland Society of Sciences and Humanities)

### **Teaching**

- MS. Course **Deep Learning** at University of Amsterdam (2017)
- BSc. Course Information Visualization at University of Amsterdam (2016)
- Supervising BSc. and MSc. Student projects in Artificial Intelligence

#### Conference and Journal Reviewing

- PAMI: IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (2016, 2017)
- NIPS: Neural Information Processing Systems (2016, 2017)
- CVPR: Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (2016, 2017)

- ICCV: International Conference on Computer Vision (2017)
- ECCV: European Conference on Computer Vision (2016)
- ACM MM: ACM Multimedia (2016)

#### **Extracurricular Activities**

- Full-Time Board Member of the Study Association for Applied Physics (2012–2013)
- Study Trip to Silicon Valley (visiting Google, Apple, Twitch and more)
- **President** of the Website Committee at the Study Assoc. for Physics (2010–2012)
- **President** of the Electronic Committee (2008–2012)
- Editor of the Quarterly Magazine "De Physics" for the Physics Study Association (2010)

#### **Languages**

- **Dutch** (Native Proficiency)
- English (Fluent Proficiency)
- **German** (Elementary Proficiency)
- French (Elementary Proficiency)

.